（鉄平(てっぺい)）アッ… アアッ…
（殴る音）
ウワッ！
（圭一(けいいち)）アアッ…
T-Takano-san!
た… 鷹野(たかの)さん
（雷鳴）
（鷹野）…られた？
...okay?
Were you able
to bury the corpse okay?
死体 上手に埋められた？
- "Curse Killing" Chapter -
Episode 04: LOST ITEM
When They Cry
Furimuita sono ushiro no
(shoumen dare)?
Kurayami ni tsume wo tatete
(yoru wo hikisaita).
Amadare wa chi no shizuku to
natte nodo wo tsutai ochiru.
Mou dokonimo kaeru
basho ga nai nara...
...kono yubi tomare
watashi no yubi ni.
Sono yubi goto tsuretette ageru.
Higurashi ga naku
akazu no mori e.
Atomodori wa mou dekinai.
死体 上手に埋められた？
Were you able
to bury the corpse okay?
な… 何を言ってるんですか？
W-What are you saying?
死体を埋めるときはね
結構 深く掘らないと―
If you don't dig pretty deep
when you bury a corpse...
...it's common for stray dogs
to track the smell and dig it up.
野犬とかが においを嗅ぎつけて
掘り返しちゃうことが多いのよ
ボケもツッコミも なし？
（圭一）は… はぁ？
You won't play along?
冗談よ フフッ… 私たち
あんまり相性は よくないみたいね
I'm joking.
It seems
we aren't very compatible.
R-Really...
そ… そうですか
この自転車 富竹(とみたけ)さんのですよね？
This is Tomitake-san's
bicycle, right?
Why do you think so?
（鷹野）
どうして そう思うのかしら？
以前 会ったとき見てますから
フレームも特徴的でしたし
I saw it when I first met him,
and the frame is unique.
これは私の自転車なのよ
ジロウさんに選んでもらったから
This is my bicycle.
Jiro-san chose it for me,
so it's true it's to his sensibilities.
センスが似てるのは
間違いないけれどね
そうなんですか
I see.
（鷹野）
私と あなたは今夜 出会わなかった
You and I did not meet tonight.
えっ？ 何言ってるんですか？
What are you saying?
You and I did not meet tonight.
私と あなたは今夜 出会わなかった
If that's okay with you,
I don't mind.
（圭一）それでいいなら
そういうことでもいいです…
That's true.
Since it's better for you that way.
そうよね　あなたにとっても
そのほうがいいでしょうから
どうして そう思うんですか？
Why do you think so?
Stop asking questions.
いちいち うるさいわね
You can't even think
about that yourself, kiddo?
それくらい
自分で考えられないの？ 坊や
じゃ おやすみなさい
Well, good night.
If she saw me,
I should've killed her.
見られていたとしたら
殺しとくべきだった
Damn...
くそ… オヤシロさまのたたりで
死んでしまえ
Die by Oyashiro-sama's curse!
I'm late.
遅刻だ
来てる
She's here.
Hey, hey. Good morning, all.
やあやあ おはよう 諸君
Ah!
（魅音(みおん)）ハハハッ…
圭ちゃん 今日も飛ばしてるね
You're flying high again today.
The festival excitement
won't go away, maybe?
（ﾚﾅ）お祭り気分が
抜けないのかな？ かな？
（圭一）お祭り気分って
俺は昨日 祭りには行ってな…
Festival excitement...
I didn't go yesterday.
Did you watch
my dance performance?
（梨花(りか)）圭一は ちゃんと ボクの
演舞 見ててくれましたですか？
Yeah, he saw it.
You didn't notice?
（ﾚﾅ）うん ちゃんと見てたよ
梨花ちゃん 気づかなかったかな？
だから…
Like I said...
Kei-chan was watching,
even ignoring dorky Shion's lure.
（魅音）圭ちゃんに
詩音(しおん)のあんぽんたんが―
ちょっかい出してきたのを
無視してね
She looked like a total loser!
詩音のヤツ ざまあなかった
（富田(とみた)）それで 射的屋の対決って
どうなったんですか？
How did the shooting
range match go?
Tomitake got last place after all.
あれは
結局 富竹(とみたけ)がビリだったのですよ
みんなで
楽しく罰ゲームをしましたです
We all had fun playing
the punishment game.
梨花ちゃんも 実質
ビリみたいなものだったじゃない
It seemed like Rika-chan
was in last place too.
But to get the gum
and turn it around...
でも
起死回生の大技でガムをゲットとは
You're our club member
all right. Well done.
さすが 我が部の部員 見事だったよ
Thank you so much, Keiichi-kun.
（ﾚﾅ）本当に ありがとうね 圭一君
（圭一）えっ？
な… 何が？
F-For what?
あのでっかい ぬいぐるみ
すっごく うれしかった
That huge stuffed toy!
I was so happy.
大事に 枕元に置いてるんだよ
I put it next to my pillow
to take care of it.
What about a stuffed toy?
ぬいぐるみが どうしたって？
圭一君が落としたんだよ
カッコよかった
You knocked it down.
You were so cool.
What are you talking about?
さっきから何の話だよ？
大体 俺…
（戸の開く音）
Besides, I...
（知恵(ちえ)）
は～い 午後の授業 始めますよ
Okay!
We're starting afternoon class.
- Yes.
- Class leader, please.
委員長 号令
（魅音）は～い
Right!
（知恵）
まず こっちだけ考えてみて
Think about this part only.
おい レナ
（ﾚﾅ）うん？
Hey, Rena.
昨日の祭りだけどさ　俺
いつごろ みんなと合流したっけ？
About yesterday's festival...
What time did I meet you all?
境内で
梨花ちゃんと話してたじゃない
Weren't you talking
to Rika-chan at the shrine?
うん 巫女(みこ)さん姿の梨花ちゃんと
楽しそうに話してた
Yeah, happily talking as she was
dressed as a shrine maiden.
梨花ちゃんと話してたのか？
I was talking to Rika-chan?
Right, and then?
（知恵）そう そしたら…
（梨花）み～
梨花ちゃんと… 話してたのか？
I was talking to Rika-chan?
圭一とですか？
With you?
ああ 梨花ちゃんは
魅音たちが来る前から―
Yeah, we were talking before
Mion and the others came, right?
俺と話してたんだな？
いつ どこで俺に会ったんだ？
When and where
did you meet me?
I met you...
圭一と会ったのは―
...when I left the meeting hall with
the village headman and others.
集会所から 村長さんたちと
出てきたときなのです
（魅音）
なんたって もう びっくりだよ
- I was so surprised!
- And then? And then?
（ﾚﾅ）それで それで？
（魅音）それでさ
（生徒）うん 分かった またね
（生徒）またね
See you.
Bye, Teacher!
先生 さようなら
なあなあ
久しぶりに やらないか？ 部活
Hey, want to have club
since it's been a while?
うん やろう やろう！
（梨花）み～！
Yeah, let's do it!
Mi.
（ﾚﾅ）部活 部活
（梨花）み～ み～ み～
- Club, club, club, club!
- Mi, mi, mi, mi!
（圭一）なあ 沙都子(さとこ)
久々に どうだよ？ パ～ッとさ
Hey, Satoko. Why not
do it for a change, come on.
Well, I appreciate
the invitation, but...
（沙都子）その… お気持ちは
うれしいでございますけど
You too for a change.
沙都子もさ たまには…
放っておいてくださいまし
（圭一）うん？
Please leave me alone.
（沙都子）私だって…
（泣き声）
I also...
帰ってこないんだろう？
He hasn't come back, right?
あいつ
That guy.
Who hasn't come back?
帰ってこないって 誰がですの？
誰って… お前の叔父さん
Who? Your uncle.
（沙都子）
何を言ってますの？ 圭一さんは
What are
you saying, Keiichi-san?
When are you
saying he disappeared?
あいつが いつ
いなくなったっていうんですの？
だって 昨日
あいつは帰ってこなかったろう？
Because he didn't
come back yesterday, right?
I really don't understand
what you're saying!
圭一さんが何を言ってるのか
全然 分かりませんでしてよ！
さ… 沙都子こそ
何を言ってんだよ？
A-And what are
you saying, Satoko?
だって あの男は…
Because that man...
He...
あいつは…
Even yesterday,
he did a lot of mean things!
昨日だって
私に いっぱい意地悪した
どなって わめいて
作ったご飯を投げられた
He yelled, screamed, and
threw the food I cooked at me!
熱かった 汚かった…
汚れたあとのお掃除も私がした
It was hot... It was dirty...
I even cleaned up the mess.
I... I...
私が… 私が…
No way...
そんな… あいつ いるのか？
He was there?
沙都子…
Satoko...
（魅音）ねえ 圭ちゃん
（圭一）えっ？
Hey, Kei-chan.
沙都子の叔父さんが
帰ってこないって―
What do you mean Satoko's
uncle isn't coming back?
なに？
（圭一）あっ…
Why?
どうして？ なんで
帰ってこないのかな？ かな？
Why wouldn't
he come back? Why?
圭ちゃん
言ってることが さっきから変
Kei-chan, what you're
saying is strange.
帰ったらね 今日は久しぶりに
レナ 宝探しに行くつもりなんだ
Going home, I plan to go treasure
hunt since it's been a while.
Mi-chan's coming too.
魅ぃちゃんも来るんだよ
Come with us. Naturally,
you have no right to refuse.
圭ちゃんも一緒に行こう
もちろん拒否権はないからね
（魅音とレナの はなうた）
There's no way he's there...
いるわけ …ないだろう
じゃあね 圭一君 お家(うち)で待ってて
See you, Keiichi-kun.
Wait at home. I'll come
pick you up right away.
レナ すぐに迎えに行くから
あっ… 俺 ちょっと用事があるんだ
I've got something to do.
用事？ 何の？
Something? Like what?
何のって… 用事だよ 用事
Like what...
Just things I have to do.
用事なら なんで魅ぃちゃんが
いるうちに言ってくれなかったの？
If you do, why didn't you
say so while Mi-chan was here?
ごめん
Sorry, my head hurts a little.
ちょっと 俺 頭が痛いんだ
風邪かもしれない
I might have a cold.
だから 診療所へ行って
薬をもらってきたいんだよ
So I want to go to
the clinic and get medicine.
ホントに？
（圭一）ああ
- Really?
- Yeah.
Oh well then.
なら しかたないね
診療所に行くなら
早く行ったほうがいいと思うよ
If you're going to the clinic,
I think you should go soon.
あそこ たまに早く閉まるから
Since they
sometimes close early.
ありがとう そうするよ
Thanks. I'll do that.
You have to go to the clinic.
必ず行くんだよ 診療所
I'll go. Definitely.
行くよ ちゃんと行く
なんなら あした 診療所の
レシートを持っていってもいい
If you want, I don't mind bringing
the clinic receipt tomorrow.
（ﾚﾅ）あっ それいいね
Oh, that sounds good.
必ず もらっておいてね
レナ あした見るから
Make sure you get it.
I'll see it tomorrow.
S-Sure.
When They Cry
Satoshi
I threw the bat in the swamp.
（圭一）バットは沼に捨てた
捨てたはずなんだ
I threw it away for sure.
If I didn't kill him,
then the bat should still be here.
あいつを殺してないなら
バットは まだ ここにあるはず
やっぱり ない…
Not here, like I thought.
（ﾅｰｽ）前原(まえばら)圭一さん
診察室へ お入りください
Keiichi Maebara-san,
please enter the exam room.
Hello.
（入江(いりえ)）こんにちは
ここでお会いするのは初めてですね
It's our first time meeting here.
監督って
本当に お医者さんだったんですね
So you really were a doctor.
アハハハッ…
（圭一）すみません
Sorry.
It doesn't seem
like you have a cold.
風邪ではないようですね
（圭一）アア…
昨日のお祭りで
はしゃぎすぎましたか？
Did you have too much
fun at yesterday's festival?
Um, you also went
to the festival, right?
あの…
監督も行ったんですよね？ お祭り
ええ もちろんですよ
Yes, of course.
Despite appearances, I'm on
the Cotton Drifting committee.
私 こう見えても 綿流しの
実行委員会の役員ですからね
Did you see me?
俺に… 会いましたか？
実は私 本部で ず～っと
会長さんたちと大酒を飲んでたんで
Actually, I was drinking with the
chairman and main office staff...
そう …ですか
I see...
変わった質問をしますね
なぜですか？
You ask strange questions.
Why?
あの… こんな話
きっと変だと思うんですけど
Um, you'll probably think what
I'm about to say is weird...
...but please listen
without laughing.
笑わないで聞いてほしいんです
（入江）ええ どうぞ
Sure, go ahead.
Is it possible there's someone
who looks exactly like me?
俺と瓜二(うりふた)つな人間がいる
…なんて ありえますか？
うん？ 世界には
自分と全く同じ顔をした人間が―
I've heard at least
two people in the world...
あと２人いると
聞いたことがあります
...look exactly like each of us.
あと ドイツのおとぎ話に出てくる
ドッペルのお化けなども有名です
The doppelgänger from German
fairy tales is also famous.
ドッペルのお化け？
Doppelgänger?
Yes, I heard it's
a harbinger of misfortune.
ええ 不幸の前触れだそうです
その… 俺
昨日は お祭りに行ってないんです
Um, I didn't go to
the festival yesterday.
Is that so. It'll happen
again next year. You can...
そうでしたか
お祭りは来年もあります
そのとき…
（圭一）そうじゃなくて
That's not it.
俺は祭りに行ってないのに
みんなが言うには―
I didn't go to the festival,
but according to everyone...
俺は祭りにいたらしいんですよ
こんなことって あるんですか？
...it seems like I was there.
Can this be?
つまり 前原さんは―
So you went to
the Cotton Drifting Festival...
綿流しのお祭りに行ったけど
記憶がない …ということですか？
...but have no memory of going?
そうじゃなくて
俺は本当に祭りに行ってないんです
That's not it!
I really didn't go to the festival.
別のことをしていましたから
I was doing something else.
“お祭りの時間に神社にいなくて
よそで別の用事をしていた”
During the festival,
you weren't at the shrine...
...and were doing
something elsewhere.
Can you clearly prove that?
それを
はっきりした形で証明できますか？
ウッ… それは…
Well...
（入江）少し横になりましょうか
心を落ち着けて 楽に…
Why not lie down for a bit?
Calm down and relax...
俺は 絶対に祭りには行ってない
それは 本当に間違いないんです
I really didn't go to the festival!
I'm not mistaken for sure!
あっ… どうか落ち着いて
Please calm down.
You don't get it at all!
あんたは全然 分かってない！
分かっていますよ
前原さん 私は… 信じますから
I do get it.
Maebara-san, I will believe you.
俺が 祭りの会場にいることは
ありえない
I couldn't have been
at the festival site.
なぜなら
その時間に 俺は沙都子の叔父を…
Because at that time, I was...
殺していたからです！
...killing Satoko's uncle!
あなたが…
沙都子ちゃんの叔父さんを？
You killed Satoko's uncle?
はい… 俺が 昨日の夜 殺しました
Yes, I killed him last night.
ど… どうして そんなことを？
W-Why did you do such a thing?
沙都子を救う最も直接的な
方法だという考えに至り
To save Satoko.
I decided it was the most
straightforward way, so I did it.
実行しました
後悔は僅かもありません
I don't regret it at all.
Is that so...
そう …ですか
だから 俺は
祭りの会場にいるわけがないんです
So I couldn't have
been at the festival site.
（入江）犯行を
誰かに目撃されたということは？
Did someone witness the crime?
ないと思います
I don't think so.
目撃されてれば もう とっくに
逮捕されてるでしょうから
Because if they had, I probably
would've been arrested by now.
I'm a doctor, so I can't agree
with taking someone's life.
私は医者ですから―
人の命を奪うことを
肯定することはできません
しかし私は あなたに こう言います
（圭一）えっ？
But I will say this to you.
沙都子ちゃんを救ってくれて
ありがとう
Thank you for
saving Satoko-chan.
大丈夫 大丈夫ですよ
（圭一）は… はい…
It'll be fine, just fine.
Y-Yes...
But it's strange.
でも おかしいんです…
（入江）うん？ おかしいとは？
What's strange?
確かに殺したはずなのに…
Even though
I'm sure I killed him...
...it seems like he's alive
and is at his house.
あの男は
生きて家にいるらしいんです
Could it be someone
other than the uncle?
叔父でなく 別人である可能性は？
えっ？ そんなはずは…
That's not possible...
だって ほら
監督と一緒に 沙都子の家の前で…
Because that was him when we
were in front of Satoko's, right?
あいつですよね？
（入江）ええ…
Yes...
間違いない　事実なんです
I'm positive. It's for a fact.
この手で…
バットで殴った あの感触は―
That impact these hands felt
when I hit him with the bat...
絶対に夢や幻なんかじゃないんです
...was definitely not
a dream or an illusion!
ハァ… この話
もう少し真剣にやりましょう
Let's discuss this
a little more seriously.
その前に
紅茶でも入れてきてあげます
Before that, I'll go
make you some black tea.
It's already closing time,
so I need to let the staff go home.
診療所も終わりの時間ですからね
事務の方とかも帰してあげないと
うん？
（医師）紅茶ですね 用意します
Black tea? I'll prepare it.
（入江）イソミタールと
ブロバリンを混入させて
Please mix in
isomytal and brovarin...
味は ミルクと砂糖で
ごまかしてください
...and mask the taste
with milk and sugar.
（医師）
急激な眠気に 不信感を爆発させて
錯乱する可能性もありますが
The sudden drowsiness could
cause severe unease and mania.
その場合は 取り押さえましょう
（医師）分かりました
In that case, let's subdue him.
Understood.
The patient makes up
stories and falsehoods...
（入江）
患者は 作り話や虚言の兆候あり
特に 昨日の記憶が 完全に混乱
...and his memory of
yesterday is jumbled.
It looks like a mental disorder.
精神障害に酷似しています
ハハッ… マジで？
For real?
Thank you for
saving Satoko-chan.
沙都子ちゃんを救ってくれて
ありがとう
なにが“ありがとう”だよ
ちきしょう…
What's with the thanks?
Damn it...
ちきしょう… 死んじまえ…
Drop dead.
Doctor, trouble!
Takano-san was found!
（医師）先生 大変です！
鷹野さんが見つかりました
Takano-san? Where?
（入江）鷹野さんが？ どこで？
偶然だ… 偶然に決まってる
It's a coincidence. It has to be.
I have to first
check on his corpse.
それより
あいつの死体を確かめるのが先だ
It seems her burnt corpse was
found in the Gifu mountains.
（医師）それが 岐阜県の山中で
焼死体で発見されたらしく
Burnt corpse? Takano-san?
（入江）
焼死体？ 鷹野さんがですか？
Since it's better for you that way.
あなたにとっても
そのほうがいいでしょうから
Die by Oyashiro-sama's curse!
オヤシロさまのたたりで死んじまえ
（入江）一体 なぜ？
Why in the world...
Details aren't known yet...
（医師）
詳しくは まだ分かりませんが
県警の話では
他殺の可能性が 極めて高いと
...but the local police say
it's very likely a homicide.
I have to verify his
corpse no matter what...
ヤツの死体を確かめるしかない
（大石(おおいし)）こんばんは
（圭一）あっ…
Good evening.
なっ… 大石
Oishi.
（大石）目上の人には
そのあとに“さん”を付けると―
I believe it's appropriate to add
a "san" when referring to elders.
なお よろしいかと思いますよ
フッ…
どうぞ 私たちのことは気にせず
Please don't mind us.
森の木立だとでも思って
穴掘りをお続けになってください
Think of us as a grove of forest
trees and keep digging the hole.
Please continue.
ほら 続きをどうぞ
チャッチャと
掘っちゃってくださいよ
Please dig quickly.
I'd like you to consider those
who have to wait in the rain.
雨の中で 待たされるほうの身にも
なってほしいです
そんなに雨がイヤなら
帰ればいいだろう
If the rain's so bad,
why don't you leave?
（大石）フン…
（圭一）アアッ！
口より先に
手を動かしてください　ねえ
Please move your hands
before your mouth, okay?
くそ！
Damn it.
そうそう 人間 そういうふうに
素直じゃなきゃダメです
Yes, yes, humans must
be obedient like that.
ハァ…
いつまで掘ればいいんだよ…
How much longer
do I have to dig?
最近の若い人は体力がありませんね
Youngsters these days
don't have much strength.
Keiichi Maebara-san, your hobby
is to dig holes on rainy nights?
前原圭一さん あなたの趣味は
雨の夜の穴掘りですかな？
No one has a hobby like that...
そんな趣味のヤツ いるもんか…
（大石）今日は大雨ですから―
It's pouring today...
これ以上 いくら ぬれても
全然 分かりませんねえ
...so no one would be able to tell
how much more wet you'd get.
What kind of treasure
is buried there?
（大石）あそこに
どんな宝物が埋まってるんですかね
Could you tell me?
私に教えてくれませんか？
ンンッ… このブタ野郎が
You pig jerk...
ウワッ！
You should die by
Oyashiro-sama's curse too!
お前も オヤシロさまのたたりで
死んでしまえばいいんだ
Such a rebel.
反抗的ですねえ
これを機に少し その辺りを
お勉強してしまいましょうか
This is a good chance
to learn good behavior.
今は平和な時代ですがね
It's a peaceful time now,
but when I was your age...
私が あなたぐらいだったころは
何でも 鉄拳制裁が普通でして
...it was normal to punish
kids with hard punches.
（熊谷(くまがい)）大石さん
（大石）はいはい
Oishi-san.
Yes, yes.
Look at this.
（熊谷）これ見てください
（大石）何ですか？ こりゃ
What's this?
（熊谷）
多分 古い配水管じゃないかと
Probably an old drainage pipe.
It's quite firm to the touch.
もう かなり手応えが硬いです
これより深くってことは
ありえないと思います
I don't think we
can dig any deeper.
う～ん…
掘る場所を間違えました？
Is this the wrong place?
いえ 初めのうちは
明らかに 掘り返す感触でした
No, it definitely felt like we were
digging something back up.
ですが このくらい掘ったころから
急に硬くなりまして
But once we got this far,
it suddenly got firmer.
多分 もともと掘った穴よりも
深く掘り進んだのだと思います
I think we've probably dug
deeper than the original hole.
So in other words, you mean
that someone dug a hole here...
じゃ つまり何ですか
誰かが ここに穴を掘って―
...and covered it with dirt
without burying anything?
何も埋めずに
そのまま土をかぶせた …と？
アハハッ！ こりゃ まいったなぁ
This is a problem.
Right, Maebara-san?
ねえ？ 前原さん
“ない”って… そんな！
Not there...
No way.
It couldn't be! His corpse...
バカな　あいつの死体が…
To get my happiness,
I had done everything...
...but had done nothing
to be blamed and accused of.
The sound of footsteps
became louder every day.
Then I noticed the fact
there was no time.
I was a believer in life,
to be myself always.
And was asking
whether I would be alive.
Give me a reason
why not to adopt in this way.
Or judge me to be guilty
of so many incurable sins.
Tell me why or why not?
Complaining way too much.
Maybe I overlooked
something fatal for me.
Preview
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
足音は 過去からのささやき
Preview
Sounds of footsteps
are whispers from the past.
What is seen is
the reality in the mist.
見えるのは 霧の中のリアル
What is heard
is forgiveness to you.
聞こえるのは あなたへの許し
When They Cry.
「ひぐらしのなく頃に」
"Curse Killing" Chapter,
Episode 5: APOLOGY.
- "Curse Killing" Chapter -
Episode 05: APOLOGY
"Curse Killing" Chapter,
Episode 5: APOLOGY.
- "Curse Killing" Chapter -
Episode 05: APOLOGY
Can you believe it?
あなたは信じられますか？